Applied and decorative arts photograph collection (medals-musical instruments).
Yale University Arts Library
Applied and decorative arts photograph collection (medals-musical instruments)
1900-2005
VRC 6.2
Yale University Arts Library
17.9
43 boxes (Boxes 101-143 of 172)
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of applied and decorative arts, predominantly European and American. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by medium. Principal categories include ceramics, furniture, glass, illuminated manuscripts, and silverware. Further arranged by chronological period, country, or region. Individual artists listed, if known.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of applied and decorative arts, predominantly European and American. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Decorative arts; Photographs; Reproductions
- Medals (Box 101)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Miscellaneous works., 24 (Box 101)
  - Pisanello, (Vittore Antonio Pisano), c.1395-1455., 20 (Box 101)
- Metalwork. (Box 102)
  See also: Silverware, Arms and Armor.
  - Miscellaneous., 21 (Box 102)
  - Ancient World., 585 (Box 102)
    - Egypt., 13 (Box 102)
    - Near East., 50 (Box 103)
      - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 103)
      - Anatolia., 7 (Box 103)
      - Mesopotamia., 14 (Box 103)
        - Sumerian., 13 (Box 103)
        - Assyrian., 1 (Box 103)
      - Persia., 25 (Box 103)
        - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 103)
        - Pre-Achaemenian., 3 (Box 103)
        - Achaemenian., 4 (Box 103)
        - Sassanian., 13 (Box 103)
      - Syria-Palestine., 3 (Box 103)
    - Aegean., 27 (Box 104)
      - Miscellaneous works., 14 (Box 104)
      - Vaphio cups., 13 (Box 104)
    - Greek., 28 (Box 104)
    - Etruscan., 29 (Box 105)
    - Roman., 43 (Box 105)
    - Early Medieval., 149 (Box 106)
      - Miscellaneous works., 9 (Box 106)
      - IV Century., 34 (Box 106)
      - V Century., 10 (Box 106)
      - VI Century., 25 (Box 106)
      - VII Century., 27 (Box 107)
      - X Century., 6 (Box 107)
      - XI Century., 24 (Box 107)
        - Miscellaneous works., 9 (Box 107)
        - Pala d'Oro., 15 (Box 107)
      - XII Century., 11 (Box 107)
      - XIII Century., 3 (Box 107)
    - Islamic., 27 (Box 108)
      - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 108)
      - Persia., 17 (Box 108)
      - Turkey., 5 (Box 108)
        - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 108)
        - XIII Century., 2 (Box 108)
        - XIV Century., 1 (Box 108)
    - Merovingian., 3 (Box 109)
    - Carolingian., 24 (Box 109)
    - Barbaric., 192 (Box 110)
      - Miscellaneous works., 19 (Box 110)
      - Anglo-Saxon., 21 (Box 110)
        Includes Sutton Hoo.
      - Celtic., 38 (Box 110)
      - Scandinavian., 48 (Box 110)
      - Scythian., 38 (Box 111)
      - Visigothic., 28 (Box 111)
  - Romanesque to Modern., 812 (Box 112)
    - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 112)
    - Austria., 4 (Box 112)
      - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 112)
      - Individual artists., 2 (Box 112)
        - Hoffmann, Josef, 1870-1918., 2 (Box 112)
    - Britain., 39 (Box 112)
      Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Miscellaneous works., 34 (Box 112)
      - Known artists., 5 (Box 112)
        - Bayley, I., XVIII C., 1 (Box 112)
        - Burges, William, 1828-1881., 1 (Box 112)
        - Denman and Sons, XX C., 1 (Box 112)
        - Dresser, Christopher, 1834-1904., 1 (Box 112)
        - Knox, Archibald, c.1900., 1 (Box 112)
    - Denmark., 12 (Box 112)
    - Flanders., 82 (Box 113)
      - Miscellaneous works., 38 (Box 113)
      - Known artists., 44 (Box 113)
        - Godefroid de Huy, XII C., 7 (Box 113)
        - Hugo d'Oignies, XIII C., 6 (Box 113)
        - Nicolas of Verdun, XII C., 29 (Box 113)
        - Renier de Huy, XII C., 2 (Box 113)
    - France., 157 (Box 114)
      - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 114)
      - XII Century., 36 (Box 114)
        - Miscellaneous works., 19 (Box 114)
        - Abbe Suger Chalice., 17 (Box 114)
      - XIII Century., 26 (Box 114)
      - XIV Century., 9 (Box 115)
      - XV Century., 4 (Box 115)
      - Renaissance, general., 10 (Box 115)
      - XVI Century., 3 (Box 115)
      - XVII Century., 8 (Box 115)
        - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 115)
        - Louis XIV., 1 (Box 115)
      - XVIII Century., 40 (Box 115)
        - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 115)
        - Louis XV, 1723-1750., 11 (Box 116)
        - Louis XVI, 1750-1793., 24 (Box 116)
      - XIX to XX Century., 18 (Box 116)
        - Miscellaneous works., 8 (Box 116)
          - Anonymous artists., 3 (Box 116)
          - Known artists., 5 (Box 116)
            - Dunand, Jean, 1877-1942., 3 (Box 116)
            - Goulden, Jean, 1878-1947., 2 (Box 116)
        - Art Nouveau., 10 (Box 116)
          - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 116)
          - Known artists., 6 (Box 116)
            - Causse, J., XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 116)
            - Colonna, Edward, 1862-1948., 1 (Box 116)
            - Laporte-Blairsy, Leo, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 116)
            - Larche, Raoul, 1860-1911., 2 (Box 116)
            - Moreau-Vauthier, Gabriel Jean Paul, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 116)
    - Germany., 238 (Box 117)
      - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 117)
      - X Century., 8 (Box 117)
      - XI Century., 34 (Box 117)
        - Miscellaneous works., 23 (Box 117)
        - Essen., 8 (Box 117)
        - Hildesheim., 3 (Box 117)
      - XII Century., 63 (Box 118)
        - Miscellaneous works., 33 (Box 118)
        - Berlin., 2 (Box 118)
        - Cologne., 8 (Box 118)
        - Gross-Komburg., 2 (Box 118)
        - London., 13 (Box 118)
        - Sieburg., 5 (Box 118)
      - XIII Century., 35 (Box 119)
        - Miscellaneous works., 16 (Box 119)
        - Aachen., 11 (Box 119)
        - Marburg., 8 (Box 119)
      - XIV Century., 17 (Box 119)
      - XV Century., 24 (Box 120)
      - XVI Century., 26 (Box 120)
        - Miscellaneous works., 18 (Box 120)
        - Known artists., 8 (Box 120)
          - Holbein, Hans the younger, 1497-1543., 1 (Box 120)
          - Jamnitzer, Wenzel, 1508-1585., 1 (Box 120)
          - Krug family., 1 (Box 120)
          - Lencker, Elias, -1591., 1 (Box 120)
          - Petzolt, Hans., 1 (Box 120)
          - Praetorius, Johann, 1537-1616., 1 (Box 120)
          - Schleich, Hans., 1 (Box 120)
          - Wallbaum, Matthaus, 1554-1632., 1 (Box 120)
      - XVII Century., 18 (Box 120)
        - Miscellaneous works., 13 (Box 120)
        - Known artists., 5 (Box 120)
          - Jamnitzer, Christoph, 1563-1618., 2 (Box 120)
          - Lencker, Johannes, c.1573-1637., 1 (Box 120)
          - Mannlich, Heinrich., 1 (Box 120)
          - Schenzen, Christopher., 1 (Box 120)
      - XVIII-XIX Century., 8 (Box 120)
      - XX Century., 3 (Box 120)
        - Known artists., 3 (Box 120)
          - Brandt, Edgar, 1880-., 1 (Box 120)
          - Brandt, Marianne., 1 (Box 120)
          - Ruppel., 1 (Box 120)
    - Holland., 12 (Box 120)
      - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 120)
      - Known artists., 5 (Box 120)
        - Bellekin, Jan, XVII C., 5 (Box 120)
    - Italy., 164 (Box 121)
      - Miscellaneous works., 15 (Box 121)
      - IX to XI Century., 2 (Box 121)
      - XII Century., 8 (Box 121)
      - XIV Century., 20 (Box 121)
      - XV Century., 58 (Box 122)
        - Miscellaneous works., 37 (Box 122)
        - Known artists., 21 (Box 122)
          - Brunelleschi, circle of, 1446., 1 (Box 122)
          - Filarete, Antonio, 1396-1465., 13 (Box 122)
          - Grosso, Niccolo., 1 (Box 122)
          - Teramo di Danieli., 6 (Box 122)
      - XVI Century., 41 (Box 123)
        - Miscellaneous works., 28 (Box 123)
        - Known artists., 13 (Box 123)
          - Cellini, Benvenuto, school of., 1 (Box 123)
          - Cioli, Valerio., 3 (Box 123)
          - Civitali, Vincenzo, -1544., 1 (Box 123)
          - Cozzarelli, Giacomo., 1 (Box 123)
          - Fontana, A., -1587., 1 (Box 123)
          - Giovanni da Bologna, 1524-1608., 3 (Box 123)
          - Grosso, Niccolo., 1 (Box 123)
            See also XV Century.
          - Manno di Bastiano Sbarri., 1 (Box 123)
          - Possenti, V., 1 (Box 123)
      - XVII Century., 11 (Box 123)
        - Miscellaneous works., 9 (Box 123)
        - Known artists., 2 (Box 123)
          - Alberghetti, G. F., 1 (Box 123)
          - Serafini, Giulio., 1 (Box 123)
      - XVIII to XX Century., 9 (Box 123)
        - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 123)
        - Known artists., 2 (Box 123)
          - Alessi, XX C., 1 (Box 123)
          - Sodini, Dante, 1858--1935., 1 (Box 123)
    - Norway., 4 (Box 124)
    - Portugal., 1 (Box 124)
    - Russia., 1 (Box 124)
    - Spain., 31 (Box 124)
      - Miscellaneous works., 20 (Box 124)
      - Known artists., 1 (Box 124)
        - Dali, Salvador, 1904-1989., 1 (Box 124)
      - XVI Century., 10 (Box 124)
    - Sweden., 10 (Box 124)
    - Latin America., 7 (Box 124)
    - United States., 43 (Box 125)
      - Miscellaneous works., 27 (Box 125)
      - Known artists., 21 (Box 125)
        - Bel Geddes, Norman, XX C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Dolbeare, Edmund, active 1670-1710., 1 (Box 125)
        - Edgell, Simon, active 1713-1742., 1 (Box 125)
        - Feher, Paul, XX C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Gleason, Roswell, active 1850-1860., 1 (Box 125)
        - Graves, Michael, 1934-., 2 (Box 125)
        - Lee, Richard, active 1788-1820., 1 (Box 125)
        - Lynch, Kenneth, XX C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Revere and Sons, XVIII C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Richardson, Joseph Jr., XVIII C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Saarinen, Eliel, 1873-1950., 1 (Box 125)
        - Tiffany and Co., XIX C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Trask, I., XIX C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Van der Spiegel, Jacobus, XVII-XVIII C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Von Nessen, Walter, 1889-1947., 2 (Box 125)
        - Will, William, XVIII C., 1 (Box 125)
        - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959., 2 (Box 125)
        - Yellin, Samuel, XX C., 1 (Box 125)
- Mosaics. (Box 126)
  Includes three folders of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 126)
  - Ancient., 101 (Box 126)
    - Miscellaneous Greek and Roman., 62 (Box 126)
    - Naples., 3 (Box 127)
    - Ostia., 8 (Box 127)
    - Piazza Armerina, Sicily., 8 (Box 127)
    - Pompeii., 20 (Box 127)
  - Medieval to Renaissance Mosaics., 782 (Box 128)
    - Miscellaneous works., 30 (Box 128)
    - Cefalu., 6 (Box 128)
    - Chios., 10 (Box 128)
    - Constantinople., 103 (Box 129)
      - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 129)
      - Hagia Sophia., 53 (Box 129)
      - Imperial Palace., 12 (Box 130)
      - Kariye Djami (Chora Church)., 35 (Box 130)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 4 (Box 130)
        - Inner Narthex., 15 (Box 130)
        - Outer Narthex., 16 (Box 130)
    - Cordova., 11 (Box 131)
    - Daphni., 25 (Box 131)
    - Florence., 8 (Box 131)
      - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 131)
      - Opera del Duomo., 2 (Box 131)
      - Baptistry., 5 (Box 131)
    - Germiny des Pres., 4 (Box 131)
    - Milan., 7 (Box 131)
    - Hosios Loukas., 9 (Box 131)
    - Monreale., 18 (Box 131)
      - Cathedral., 18 (Box 132)
    - Murano., 3 (Box 132)
    - Palermo., 39 (Box 132)
      - La Martorana., 14 (Box 132)
      - La Zisa., 2 (Box 132)
      - Palazzo Reale, Capella Palatine., 23 (Box 132)
    - Pisa., 2 (Box 132)
    - Ravello., 20 (Box 132)
    - Ravenna., 298 (Box 133)
      - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 133)
      - Archiepiscopal Palace., 13 (Box 133)
      - Arian Baptistry., 13 (Box 133)
      - Mausoleum of Galla Placida., 32 (Box 133)
      - Orthodox Baptistry., 20 (Box 134)
      - S. Apollinare in Classe., 25 (Box 134)
      - S. Apollinare Nuovo., 120 (Box 135)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 1 (Box 135)
        - North Wall., 53 (Box 135)
          - Overviews., 11 (Box 135)
          - Lower zone., 18 (Box 135)
          - Upper zone., 24 (Box 135)
        - South wall., 66 (Box 136)
          - Overviews., 16 (Box 136)
          - Lower zone., 16 (Box 136)
          - Upper zone., 34 (Box 136)
      - S. Vitale., 76 (Box 137)
        - Miscellaneous views., 45 (Box 137)
        - Emperor Justinian and his retinue., 11 (Box 137)
        - Empress Theodora and her retinue., 20 (Box 137)
    - Rome., 90 (Box 138)
      - Miscellaneous locations, including the Vatican., 12 (Box 138)
      - S. Agnese., 2 (Box 138)
      - S. Clemente., 6 (Box 138)
      - Ss. Cosmos and Damian., 3 (Box 138)
      - S. Costanza., 19 (Box 138)
      - S. Giovanni Laterano., 4 (Box 138)
      - S. Maria Maggiore., 17 (Box 139)
      - S. Maria in Trastevere., 16 (Box 139)
      - S. Paolo Fuori le Mura., 1 (Box 139)
      - S. Prassede., 8 (Box 139)
      - S. Pudenziana., 2 (Box 139)
    - Salonika., 26 (Box 140)
    - Siena., 2 (Box 140)
    - Torcello., 15 (Box 140)
    - Venice., 56 (Box 141)
      - San Marco., 56 (Box 141)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 13 (Box 141)
        - Atrium., 23 (Box 141)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 12 (Box 141)
          - Creation of the world., 11 (Box 141)
        - Baptistry., 3 (Box 141)
        - Nave., 17 (Box 141)
  - Modern Mosaics., 58 (Box 142)
    - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 142)
    - Britain., 5 (Box 142)
    - Germany., 13 (Box 142)
    - Holland., 2 (Box 142)
    - Italy., 2 (Box 142)
    - Sweden., 4 (Box 142)
    - United States., 28 (Box 142)
- Musical Instruments. (Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 143)